WHISPERING CORRIDORS
This is Eun-young Hur .
l can 't answer the phone , so leave your message .
Junior , Senior ...
Junior , Senior - -
Mrs. Park , you 're still here .
l had to check something ...
l 'll be leaving soon .
l guess the new semester 's keeping you busy .
- Need any help ? - l 'm fine .
" Libray "
Hello ?
- Eun-young ? - Mrs. Park ?
Jin-ju is here .
) in-ju ?
- l don 't know . - What are you talking about ?
She 's definitely dead ...
but she 's here .
She 's been here all along .
Mrs. Park - -
Eun-young ? Hello ?
- What are you doing here ? - Uh ? Waiting foryou .
What ?
What did you say ?
- l was waiting . - For me ?
Why ?
Why were you waiting for me ?
We 're the class clerks for the week .
Jae-yi Yoon , tying to make me feel guilty , huh ?
l 'm not late though .
l 'm running 1 5 minutes early .
Of course , you 're not late . l 'm the one who came too early .
We never promised to meet here .
Why didn 't you wait in the classroom ? It 's cold out here .
l hate to go to an empty classroom . That 's creepy .
Sory .
Don 't just stand there moping .
You 'll jinx my chance of spending ...
this senior year in style .
What ? Want to become a school gate ghost ?
Come on .
What 's this ?
I 'm not sure , only that she 's possessed .
Possessed ?
You know , by the study demon - -
one with a low I.Q. though .
Were you two close ?
Whywould l hang around with that creep ?
Oh , l forgot to bring a rag .
Hey !
What ?
Give me that , fool . You don 't need to take it back with you .
Hury up .
Ji-oh !
lt 's your duty as her students .
lf any of you spread rumors ...
and defame her reputation , you will never be forgiven .
Understood ?
Don 't distract the other students with gossip .
lt 's all for the best .
Fortunately , we 're swearing ...
this oath of honor ...
before all hell breaks loose .
- Got it ? - Yes , sir .
Got it ?
Yes , sir !
You 'll take all the blame if rumors gets spread .
Understood ?
Yes , sir .
Why did she kill herself
lt 's not clear . The police need more leads .
You could kill yourself for any reason ...
but why do it at school ?
l 'm sory for being late .
The principal will assign a new teacher for room three by end of day .
Also , he will give special instructions about how to handle this matter .
Make sure this is kept confidential ...
and make sure kids don 't spread rumors .
Hey ! Are you sure ?
Did l ever lie to you ?
Yeah .
l swear this is all true .
ls that true she committed suicide ?
You can 't call it suicide just because she hung herself .
Something is fishy .
Nobody liked her , you know ?
Jin-ju is here .
Are you sure you want to give this to me ?
Isn 't it a family heirloom ?
Thanks , Jin-ju .
- Is your dad still drinking a lot ? - l don 't know .
Don 't be so cold .
Did you hear ?
Jung-sook was the first one here .
Yeah , and she wasn 't even the clerk for the week .
She was here even before the clerks .
Remember ? She had an argument with Mrs. Park last week .
Yeah ! That 's right !
Making out , you two ?
Go work in a factoy if you can 't cut it - -
Or stay home ! You hear ?
Degenerates !
" Jin-juJang "
Look at your uniform . Hands out !
You 're such a bad influence .
What 's this smell ? Perfume ?
lt figures.The nerve ! Just like her shaman mother .
Miss Hur ?
A penny for your thoughts .
You weren 't answering .
Oh , were you calling me ?
You 're the only teacher with that name .
Sory , l still feel like a student here .
Really ?
So , she used to beyour senior year homeroom teacher ?
Her death must have shocked you .
She said she had something to check . l assumed it was important .
What was she checking ?
l 'm not sure ...
but she was looking at her class agenda book .
She 's definitely dead ...
but she 's here .
She 's been here all along .
lt 's not that l don 't want to call the spirits with you ...
it 's just so childish that l don 't want to do it anymore .
Do it on your own .
Nobody else can call the spirits .
Just this one time . Please ?
Oh , mighty spirit , come to us .
Draw us a circle if you are here .
Draw us a circle if my friend is a virgin ...
or draw an " X " if she is not .
Having fun ?
Get your asses over here .
What the heck is he doing in here ?
Hasn 't senior year put some sense into you ?
lf you 're so psychic , make a living out ofit .
Why bother with school ?
l asked her for my grades .
Ji-oh , are you a shaman or witch doctor ?
Then get better grades foryourself .
You 're lowering the class average .
Get out of my sight .
Who is it ?
Who 's the smart ass who just laughed ?
l see .
Eveyone on your desks , now !
l 'll teach you a lesson .
Arms up !
Can 't you greet your new homeroom teacher with respect ?
Homeroom teacher ?
Due to personal matters , Mrs. Park is unable to continue her duties .
l will be taking over , you hear ?
This means two things .
One ...
you will have a better chance of getting into college .
Two ...
you won 't have any personal life for a year .
lt 's the new semester of your senior year ...
so you 're a little excited .
l advise you to get rid of such cheap sentimentalisms .
Those are luxuries a senior should do without .
Got it ?
My motto is : " Keep your own place . "
This will be the class motto from now on .
You 're each other 's rival ...
but frankly speaking , you 're each other 's enemy .
The worst enemy in war is yourself .
When you can defeat your inner enemy ...
then you can be a true winner .
l 've re-scheduled the exams for tomorrow .
Be prepared .
Get used to it and stop whining !
lt 's for evaluation purposes .
So , don 't get stressed out , all right ?
lf you don 't have what it takes , well ... l got nothing to say then .
Class dismissed . Start cleaning up .
Dang , wish we had exams eveyday .
- What ? - Then school ends early .
Exams never kept you from leaving early anyway .
You 're always the first to dive out ofthe classroom .
- It 's better to chill after exams . - Whatever .
- Ow , ouch . - Got stuck ?
Damn ! It 's blocked .
Didn 't we get pierced on the same day ?
Mine is fine though .
Ouch .
Stop whining . See ? It 's going in .
Stop it ! It hurts .
l 'm tying to take it out , you slut . Want a bloody slit up your nose ?
Hey !
What areyou staring at ?
Didn 't you hear me ?
What 's all the fuss ?
You psychic , mind your own business !
" Eun-young Hur "
l 'll ask them to be replace the missing yearbooks .
So , you 're an alumni , right ?
How did you know ?
You were pretty famous as the student with looks and brains .
My grades were so-so ...
and the yearbook shows prettier girls .
Why did you choose to be a teacher ?
l guess it 's not so bad after all .
Can l drop the formalities when we 're alone ?
lf you insist .
The teachers often compare us to each other ...
but they say l 'm prettier and smarter .
You 're definitely prettier but do you also get good grades ?
Yes , l 'm applying for Seoul National University .
What major ?
Does it matter ? It 's the best school in the nation .
There must be something that interests you .
Nothing special . Besides , l hate studying .
Once l get accepted , l 'm done with books .
A degree from that school is like a gold card for eveything .
Even though you 'll be done with books , it wouldn 't hurt reading Joyce .
How come you 're still here ?
l didn 't have the chance ...
to thank you from earlier .
You like to do girlie things , don 't you ?
Thanks anyway .
Have a seat .
Practicing for art school ?
Nope .
l 'm supposed to have no talent .
How would you know ?
According to my mom ...
l don 't have any talent and it is a waste of time .
Well , actually , she 's right .
This is just for fun .
Can l see ?
No . It 's embarrassing .
l guess it is embarrassing .
You 're breaking my heart .
Okay , l 'll show it toyou .
l told you so .
Why paint something so scay ?
Well ...
school can be ...
an horrific experience for ...
both students and teachers .
Like witnessing a tragic death .
Do you get it ?
l guess that 's why ...
l can 't forget the image of Mrs. Park hanging there .
lt 's like an inspiration .
Terrific .
What is ?
- You are . You speak like an artist . - You 're kidding .
l can 't even paint .
Of course you can . You need to improve your skills ...
butyou know how to control light .
Bad paintings drain the life out of their objects ...
because they lack this quality .
This painting has it .
You have a good eye .
That 's the most important element for a good artist .
You must have studied painting .
A long time ago .
When ? In junior high ?
No , longer than that .
l quit though .
No talent , like someone l know .
Jae-yi , will you teach me how to paint ?
You can join me when you get bored ofteaching .
No ?
l - -
ls it a yes or no ?
All right , if you insist .
Promise that you 'll do as l say .
Now you sound like Mr. Oh .
We 're mortal enemies .
Don 't tell me you 're his niece ?
lsn 't this great , Jin-ju ?
Miss Hur .
What are you doing at my desk ?
ls this your desk ?
Yes .
What brings you to our classroom ?
This used to be my homeroom .
lt brings back memories .
lt 's still pretty much the same .
l didn 't do that .
l know. l did it .
Was this your desk ?
No .
lt was my friend Jin-ju 's .
Excuse me .
Jin-ju , this will be your desk forever .
Here .
l found her address in my diary . l want to meet her family .
l 'll explain it later .
lt 's really important .
l 'll drop by later . Bye , Mom .
Looking for an old flame ?
No , a girlfriend from high school .
Lost touch after graduation ?
Kind of .
Can 't call that friendship .
Guess it happens when you 're busy .
She died in high school .
Oh , the student who committed a suicide ?
Was she your friend ?
Yes , you were in Mrs. Park 's class .
But why areyou looking for her family ?
Just curious .
Go to the school storage room .
Her ghost haunts the place . You 'll get to meet her in person .
A couple of girls claim that they 've seen the ghost .
So she died in the art room ?
lt used to be the art room .
She must have jinxed the place .
Construction workers have been sick or hurt .
That 's why that building is abandoned .
Of all the places to die , why choose school ?
Ji-oh , you piece of shit !
The vice principal almost had a heart attack ...
when he found this in the art room .
How would you explain this ?
Answer me !
Areyou trying to fuck with me ?
- No , sir . - Don 't bullshit me !
You degenerate !
You must be a psycho , a maniac .
ls that what your parents teach you at home ?
Do they let you create such monstrosities ?
Get out of my sight . You disgust me !
Go !
Get the heck out of here !
Get out !
l dare you .
You psycho .
You wanna die ?
Die ! Die !
You filthy - -
l told your mom not to wory .
She 's sensitive about your first exam as a senior .
lf you 've finished , l would like to be excused .
What 's the hury ?
l should get back to my books .
Don 't be a stranger to your own teacher .
A woman should be like cotton candy .
" Teacher 's lounge "
So-young .
Do you know where l can find that painting of your classmate 's ?
lt must have been trashed . Mad Dog chewed it to pieces .
Mad Dog ?
l apologize . That 's what we call Mr. Oh .
Shouldn 't it be " pervert " ?
- Whose painting is it ? - Ji-oh 's .
l see .
lt 's for the best . No more painting for me .
- Giving up painting ? - No where to paint .
There is one place .
The teachers will never know .
Never mind .
What ?
- Let 's go . - Where ?
l was just joking .
You can 't go there .
Why not ?
lt 's a mess , cob webs and rats .
We 'll just take a look .
Are you nuts ? The place is haunted .
Then stay here . l 'll check for ghosts , okay ?
Who taught you to smoke ?
No one . Ever see me learn from anyone ?
How brave of you to set foot in this haunted place .
l prefer ghosts .
Besides , didn 'tyou know ?
l 'm the ghost .
So this is the haunted place for avoiding teachers , right ?
Then lend me some space . l need a place to paint .
l 've been banned from the art room .
Don 't you want to kill him ?
Yeah , why don 't you do the honors ?
You have to pay the rent .
l found it first , so it 's mine .
l 'll keep it secret .
Pay the rent ?
Aren 't you a rich girl ?
l 'm sorry .
l came to ask you something and the door was open .
lt 's okay . Have a seat .
You haven 't been put in detention .
Wow , someone did quite a number on this .
Why bring it here ?
l was curious , but the teacher 's lounge is - -
lt is uncomfortable there , isn 't it ?
l guess l still feel like a student .
Think so ?
Perhaps it 's more than that .
Do you usually sketch a student 's face ?
l like their expressions .
Didn 't you have something to ask ?
Uh ... About this painting - -
Hello , there .
What were you saying ?
l was in the art club when l was in high school .
So you used to paint ?
No , l sculpted faces in plaster .
Sculpted ?
Yes .
l used to sculpt my friend 's face as a hobby .
Must have been a great gift .
l hope theywere .
- Excuse me . - Just a moment .
Here . Take it .
Don 't give up painting .
" Keep your place "
Park , So-young . School rank , first place .
Go ahead and give her a big round of applause .
Kim , Jung-sook .
Your class rank is second place , yet your school rank is 25th .
What the heck are you doing ?
What 's the use of studying long hours if you 're not paying attention .
lf you don 't have the brains , ask So-young for some tips ...
Class head .
Hand these out after l 'm done .
- Attention ! - Don 't bother .
How can the class with the school 's best student have the worst score ?
Don 't greet me until you improve the class average , you hear ?
Do you have Mrs. Park 's class agenda book ?
No , but perhaps Mr. Kim would know .
Night patrolling with female teachers will be fun .
That will be the end of lonely nights though .
What do you think ? Not bad , huh ?
What 's wrong ?
Too much dust . Look .
You have a vain side toyou , don 'tyou ?
Aren 't you scared of this place - -
ghosts and all ?
Not at all .
Actually , l feel at ease , like home .
Really ?
Why ? Don 't you ?
Anything you say .
Strange .
Damn it !
Ow !
What the - - Ow !
Who 's there ?
Who areyou ?
Order !
l 'll be filling in for Mr. Oh today , so behave .
- He didn 't come in today ? - Is anything wrong ?
How should l know ?
Kim , Nuri !
- Choi , Anna ! - Here !
He must have fallen asleep in the sauna .
Maybe he 's sleeping pretty deeply .
A ghost must have gotten him .
Kim , Jung-sook . Kim , Jung-sook ! Is that her seat ?
- Yes , sir . - Is she absent ?
She hasn 't come in yet .
What gives ? She 's never late .
lt was Mad Dog 's turn . The ghost got him .
l 'm positive .
Where did you get that from ?
Do l still look like your friend ?
Hey ...
- Stop it . - Isn 't that Jung-sook ?
l 'm sure he was killed last night .
What makes you think so ?
l feel it .
Just like the day Mrs. Park died .
l feel like l killed Mad Dog myself .
You think l was possessed ...
and murdered Mad Dog ?
Whoever did it ...
aren 't you glad that he 's gone ?
Look , l 'm not joking .
What if l 'm really possessed ?
What shall l do ?
Ji-oh , don 't be so serious .
Don 't wory . He 's a die-hard .
He must be playing hooky .
Do as l say , Eun-young .
You 'll thank me one day .
You won 't regret it .
You have to hang around with the right friends .
She 's no good foryou .
- Looking for this ? - Yes .
What for ?
lt 's only going to depress you .
" Class agenda book "
" Lim , Ji-oh "
" Applying for art school "
" Lacks the ability and the desire to apply for college "
Oh , it 's you , So-young .
Any problems ?
No , nothing .
Did you say there were spare yearbooks ?
No , they suddenly disappeared .
So stupid .
So typical of the school system .
Have you found the painting ?
Huh ?
Of Ji-oh 's . You wanted to see it .
Oh , yes. l did .
Do you know Ji-oh well ?
Not much . She just sits right next to me .
Why ?
Nothing special , apart from her ability to call the spirits .
Call the spirits ?
Probably her way of getting attention .
lf you 're so curious , she 's in the storage room , painting .
What 's this noise ?
What areyou doing ?
Get your ass over here .
Now ! l said now !
What brings you here ?
So , now you 're following me .
Forget it .
l have nothing against you .
Never avoided you either .
Let 's just say we 're different .
Meet me after evening studies .
Why ?
Can 't we talk now ?
ls your sister coming to pick you up ?
Sister ?
Sorry , was that your stepmother ?
She looks so young .
Jung-sook ...
mind your own business .
ls your real mom still in the loony bin ?
Bitch !
To think l took pity on you .
You think you could beat me ?
Guess again .
You don 't have what it takes .
We 're different .
Got it ?
Loser .
Your mother 'll save you , after all she 's a shaman .
l never spread those rumors about your mom .
lt was Mrs. Park who told me .
l was scared of being ostracized for taking your side .
l never thought that anything bad would happen toyou .
She threatened to expel you ...
for my sake .
l was afraid .
I 'm so sorry , Jin-ju .
" To my best friend , Eun-young , from Jin-ju "
Does it look like you ? Don 't ever lose it .
l told you l 'm Ji-oh .
Then where did you get those bells ?
A friend gave them to me .
Jin-ju is dead .
This is where she died 9 years ago .
l saw it .
She couldn 't have given those bells to you .
What are you talking about ?
These are from Jae-yi , Jae-yi Yoon !
What 's wrong ? What happened ?
" To my best friend Jin-ju , from Eun-young , 1989 "
We used to be close .
So close that we shared oursecrets .
But then ...
teachers started comparing us ...
and we drifted apart .
She become distant .
l never reached out to her .
But ...
l never thought ...
it would come to this .
lt 's all my fault .
" To my best friend Jin-ju , from Eun-young , 1989 "
" Kang , Hyun-soo "
" Park , Ji-sung "
You should never have returned .
" Eun-young has returned as a teacher "
" Once again Mrs. Park has become the homeroom teacher "
" Ji-oh hasn 't deserted me "
You 're not Jae-yi ...
nor Jin-ju neither .
You 're not Eun-young .
l 've always been - -
and still am - - Eun-young .
You can never be the Eun-young l used to know .
You 'll become just like Mrs. Park .
You 're wrong .
l 'm still Jin-ju 's friend Eun-young .
lt 's no use now .
l don 't want to hurt you ...
but l don 't have a choice .
Jae-yi !
You could never kill me .
Without you , l can continue being a student .
Stop It .
What good would it do ? You are a ghost !
At first , l just wanted have a yearbook .
But then l wanted more .
l needed a friend ...
who really understood and cared about me .
But not this way !
You 're not human .
l only had to ...
keep the classroom full , like these desks .
Nothing more .
For the past 9 years ...
no one suspected my identity .
lt didn 't matter whether l was human or not .
l just had to fill the empty seats ...
and be there during head counts .
l understand ...
but you have to stop now .
You don 't get it ...
now that you 're a teacher .
What happened toyou will never happen again .
l don 't think so .
lt always has and always will .
Trust me Jin-ju . l 'll do my best .
l will . Trust me .
lt 'll take a lot more than just you to make a change .
Stop it , Jae-yi .
Stop !
l don 't care if you 're a ghost or not .
You 've gone too far this time .
Don 't wory , Ji-oh .
Eveything will go back to normal .
We can never ...
go back .
Don 't wory , Ji-oh .
You have to stop .
l can 't let you continue harming the teachers ...
for my sake .
l 've waited so long foryou .
l can 't give up now .
Stop !
lt 's no use , Ji-oh .
Lay a finger on her and l 'm gone .
Stop the horrors .
l think l can understand you now ...
but the bloodshed has to end .
So many things l wanted to do .
l pined for a friend ...
who would reach out to me .
Finally , l 've met that friend .
l love you , too ...
really ...
but , please , stop .
Leave the rest to us .
Rest in peace , Jae-yi .
l never intended to hurt anyone .
l just wanted a friend ...
and to leave with good memories .
That 's all .
l can 't stay like this ...
because l 'm not a human anymore .
l 'm sorry .
We will ...
never forget you .